- [Instructor] Atoms are like units of state.
They're like independent pieces of data
that we can update and to which we can subscribe.
So whenever there's a change in the states in an atom,
each subscribed component is re-rendered with the new value.
In this video, we learned to divide the state into atoms.
So we're going to look at the syntax, which is very simple.
It's like an object with two keys, two properties.
So the key will contain a unique ID,
which is used for debugging, persistence,
and other advanced features.
And you must also specify a default value.
So I'm going to copy this syntax
and we're going to go to our start projects.
And here you're going to see that the source code
is very familiar because you have several state variables
but which is available at the top level
of the root component, which isn't the best practice.
Instead, we want to manage the state outside
of every components
and allow every component to subscribe
to the different pieces of states
which are defined with the atoms.
So first, let's just make sure that we import
from the library, recoil.
That's going to be atom.
And we're going to add our first atom right here.
And the way we're going to proceed
is that every local state variable
is going to be replaced with an atom.
So first it's going to be the list.
So I'm going to name this one list
and I'm going to name the key the exact same way
which will be list.
And for the default value,
it's going to be this array of items.
I'm going to create another item
which will be to then manage the state for all.
And here for the features.
Basically we have two type of lists.
One which is to display the full list,
and another list which is to display the list
of items filtered.
And we have another variable here
which is used to indicate when the list is filtered.
So I'm going to define another atom
to manage this one separately.
So that's going to be filterStates.
And for this one, we have a default value, which is false.
So I'm going to do just like this one, it's going to be false.
And last, we have also an input value.
So I'm going to define this one below.
And this one, I'm going to actually name this one
a bit differently.
It's going to be inputValue for this atom.
And then for the default value is going to be an empty string,
just like this one.
So we're not going to remove that just yet.
So that's going to be actually part two.
We have just created atoms
in order to contain pieces of state,
and this is just step one.
So the thing to keep in mind is that atoms
contain the source of truth of your application state.
Next we're going to learn more about recoil,
and learn about how to read the state from the components.